Finding aid to the Stephen G. Tilley papers CA.MS.01198
Smith College Archives
Stephen G. Tilley papers
1964-2014
Smith College Archives
Stephen G. Tilley
CA.MS.01198
8.5 linear feet (6 record cartons, 2 letter document boxes)
Professional papers of Stephen G. Tilley, salamander herpetologist and Myra Sampson emeritus professor of biological sciences at Smith College.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Stephen G. Tilley
Biographical / Historical
Stephen G. Tilley received his B.S. from Ohio State University in 1965 and Ph.D. from University of Michigan in 1970, focusing his research on salamanders. He taught at Smith College from the early 1980s until early 2000s, and is currently the Myra Sampson emeritus professor of biological sciences at Smith College. He is also the author of many scientific journal articles and books on herpetological studies.
Content Description
Professional papers of Stephen G. Tilley, Myra Sampson emeritus professor of biological sciences at Smith College. Includes correspondence, research data, conference papers, teaching materials (syllabi, notes), research reports and other materials.
Biology--Study and teaching (Higher)--Massachusetts --Northampton.; Tilley, Stephen G.; Herpetologist; Stephen G. Tilley; Stephen G. Tilley
- Thesis data, figures, correspondence, and notes, 1970; 29 folders (29 folders) (Box 1)
- Published manuscripts (notes, data, drafts, and reviewer comments), 1972-2009; 24 folders (24 folders) (Box 1, Box 2)
- Published research (notes, data, drafts, reviewer comments), 1982-1996; 18 folders (18 folders) (Box 2, Box 3)
- Unpublished research (notes, data, drafts), 1966-2001; 59 folders (59 folders) (Box 3, Box 4)
- Blakeslee grant funding and budget information, 1991-2008; 12 linear feet (12 folders) (Box 4)
- Collecting permits and applications, 1964-2014; 29 folders (29 folders) (Box 4)
- Manuscript reviews and proposals, 1976-2001; 24 folders (24 folders) (Box 5)
- NSF materials (budgets, grants, correspondence, proposals, and reports), 1985-2001; 11 folders (11 folders) (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous grants, 1968-1992; 7 folders (7 folders) (Box 5)
- Correspondence, A-Z, 1964-1998; 27 folders (27 folders) (Box 6)
- Smith College sabbatical paperwork and correspondence, 1980-2007; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6)
- Research trip notes and correspondence, 1966-1982; 2 folders (2 folders) (Box 6)
- Lecture notes and publicity, 1966-1992; 2 folders (2 folders) (Box 6)
- Materials for Plethodontid course at Highlands Biological Station, 1983-2008; 10 folders (10 folders) (Box 7)
  General
  Folder on the 2008 class only contained personal student information, and was discarded.
- Salamander conference correspondence and organizational information, 1972; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7)
- Plethodontid symposiums and herpetological society meetings, 1966-1998; 7 folders (7 folders) (Box 8)